# FLORINDA MELÉNDEZ RODRÍGUEZ



# DATA ANALYST | MOLECULAR BIOLOGIST

# INFORMATION

- - Madrid (Spain)
- +34 678 12 24 83
- (a) fcmelrod@gmail.com
- (a) github.com/Flori-87
- in linkedin.com/in/florinda-melendez
- portfolio portfolio

A passionate researcher, turned into a self-sufficient person during my PhD. Now I am enhancing my career towards Data Analysis using Python, SQL, APIs and I want to grow as a data analyst. Creating a good work environment through teamwork, motivation and empathy is amongst my main values.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

August 2020 - Present

# Biostatistician

Savana Médica (Madrid, Spain)

- Interpretation of needs from Protocols and SAPs
- Extraction of information from databases
- Data cleaning, wrangling and statistical analysis
- Elaboration and review of technical documents
- Interpretation and **presentation** of results

July 2019 – February 2020

### Postdoctoral

Research Unit of Santa Cristina Hospital/Health Research Institute "Princesa" (Madrid, Spain)

- Responsible for several project lines
- Experimental design and data analysis
- **Teaching** activities and co-supervision of students

November 2011 – April 2019

#### Ph.D. student

Research Unit of Santa Cristina Hospital/Autonomous University of Madrid (Spain)

- Participation in the EU Consortium "EpoCan"
- Writing of original articles and reviews
- Award of fellowship for predoctoral contracts funded by the Ministry of Economy in Spain
- Publications

# **KEY SKILLS**

#### Language

- ✓ Spanish: Native
- ✓ English: Intermediate (B2 level)

Hard skills













Machine Learning



Soft skills

- Teamwork
- Motivation
- Leadership
- Hard-working Initiative

# DATA ANALYSIS PROJECTS

# Data cleaning

Data cleaning, wrangling and analysis techniques using Pandas, Numpy and Matplotlib libraries and regex.

### Data pipelines

Pipeline generation to analyze a dataset based on parameters received through command flags in shell.

### Geocoding

Use of MongoDB, GeoJSON points, Folium and Google API as the main tools to find the best location.

### Image segmentation

Image processing through segmentation technique using Numpy, Pillow and SciPy libraries.

### API development

Updating and recommendations using NLP of a database in MongoDB using an API by HTML requests.

### Supervised Machine Learning (ML) for regression

Algorithms of supervised ML for regression in Scikitlearn library and H2O AutoML function to predict prices.

#### Neural Networks (NN) for classification

Image preprocessing and classification by training a convolutional NN to predict the tumor type using an instance on Google Cloud platform.

# **EDUCATION**

May 2020

**Data Analytics Bootcamp** Ironhack (Madrid, Spain)

April 2019

Ph.D. degree (Cum laude) Autonomous University of Madrid (Spain)

March 2013

Experiment design and analysis of variance Health Research Institute "Princesa" (Madrid, Spain)

June 2011

Master's in Molecular and Cellular Biology Autonomous University of Madrid (Spain)

July 2010

Bachelor's degree in Biotechnology Pablo de Olavide University (Sevilla, Spain)